¡ 哎哟！
¡Voy!
今天我们来这里是为了纪念、陪伴这位伟大的球员。
Today we are here to honor, to accompany this great player.
Hoy estamos aquí para homenajear, para acompañar a este gran jugador.
不是在告别，不是在撤退，陪他到那个地方。
not in a goodbye, not in a retreat, to accompany him to that place.
no en un adiós, no en un retiro, para acompañarlo a ese sitio.
很少有人拥有的特权，阿根廷国家队的偶像。
of privilege that few have, of idol of the Argentine National Team.
de privilegio que tienen pocos, de ídolo de la Selección Nacional Argentina.
安天使迪玛利亚！
Ángel Di María!
¡Ángel Di María!
天使！
¡Ángel!
或者干脆...！
Or simply...!
¡O simplemente...!
菲力！
Filet!
¡Fileo!
嘿，你个咩咩叫的！
Hey, you bleat!
¡Eh, te balas!
亲爱的爸爸，我知道他们从来不希望你白天来。
Dear dad, I know they never wanted you to arrive during the day.
Querido papá, sé que nunca quisieron que llegues de día.
但今天它来了。
But today it arrived.
Pero hoy llegó.
长达16年多的职业生涯就此结束。
A career that lasted more than 16 years has come to an end.
Una carrera que duró más de 16 años ha llegado a su fin.
有很多批评，但你总是用头撞墙。
There was a lot of criticism, but you always kept banging your head against the wall.
Fueron muchas las críticas, pero siempre seguiste dándote la cabeza contra la pared
经过如此多的努力，它破裂了。
And after so much effort, it broke.
Y después de tanto esfuerzo, se rompió.
破墙去哪儿了？
Where did breaking the wall go?
¿A dónde ha sido romper la pared?
墙破了。
The wall broke.
Se rompió la pared.
我没有他的姓氏。
I don't have his last name.
No me le apellido.
啊，难的已经过去了。
Ah, the hard one is gone.
Ah, se fue el duro.
皮切，多好的一幅画啊，天使。
Piche, what a painting, angel.
Piche, qué cuadro, ángel.
你曾效力过六家具乐部，多年来你因为不同的原因而遭受苦难。
You went through six clubs and there were many years that you suffered for different reasons.
Pasaste por seis clubes y fueron muchos los años que sufriste por distintas razones.
但足球总是有回报的。
But football always pays off.
Pero el fútbol siempre da recompensa.
你实现了你最伟大的目标：世界杯和更多的冠军。
You achieved your greatest goal, the World Cup and many more titles.
Obtuviste tu mayor meta, la Copa del Mundo y muchos títulos más.
35 个标题。
35 titles.
35 títulos.
毫无疑问，你在选择上迈出了一大步。
Without a doubt you made a huge step in the selection.
Sin duda hiciste un paso enorme en la selección.
以及其他将永远被标记的俱乐部、国家和地方。
as well as in other clubs and countries and places that will be marked forever.
como también en otros clubes y países y lugar el que quedarán marcados por siempre
但凭借你那充满魔力、活泼的眼睛。
But with your magic, lively eye.
Pero con tu magia, ojo vivo.
几千个奖杯，但是……这怎么可能不是？
Thousands of trophies, but... How can this not be?
Miles de trofeos, pero... ¿Cómo éste no?
怎么没有这个呢？
How is there not this one?
¿Cómo éste no hay?
我想这是我唯一想要的东西。
I think this was the only thing I wanted.
Creo que éste era lo único que quería.
在泪水和痛苦之间，我们怀着巨大的爱和感情向您告别。
Between tears and pain we say goodbye to you with enormous love and affection.
Entre lágrimas y dolor te despedimos con un amor y un cariño enorme.
对于一个为了一件T恤而献出生命的人还有什么可说的呢？
What more can be said about a man who gave his life for a t-shirt?
¿Qué más se puede decir de un hombre que dio su vida por una camiseta?
是的，对很多人来说，你不是英雄，更不是国家队的神。
Yes, for many you were not the hero or much less a god in the national team.
Sí que para muchos no fuiste el héroe o mucho menos un dios en la selección.
但在我心里你永远是世界上最好的父亲和球员。
But in my heart you will always be the best father and player in the world.
Pero en mi corazón siempre vas a ser el mejor padre y jugador del mundo.
我很高兴您能够享受您应得的和一直想要的职业生涯。
I am very glad that you were able to enjoy your career as you deserved and always wanted.
Me alegro muchísimo que hayas podido disfrutar tu carrera como lo merecés y siempre quisiste.
我记得那些夜晚，当你来训练时，热切地告诉我发生在你身上的一切。
I remember those nights when you came to train and eagerly told me everything that had happened to you.
Me acuerdo esas noches que venías a entrenar y con ansias me contabas todo lo que te había pasado.
我相信你的职业生涯将在未来标志着一些非常重要的事情。
I am sure that your career will mark something very important in the future.
Estoy segura que tu carrera va a marcar algo muy importante en el futuro.
很多人会因为你的工作而记住你，但我会记得你是那个在海滩街上玩耍的男孩。
Many will remember you for your work, but I will remember you as that boy who played on the street at the beach.
Muchos te van a recordar por tu trabajo, pero yo te voy a recordar como ese nene que jugaba en la calle a la playa.
几年后，他与队友一起赢得了世界杯。
with a rock, who years later won the World Cup with his teammates.
con una roca, al cual años después ganaba la Copa del Mundo con sus compañeros.
成为阿根廷历史上最好的球员之一。
being one of the best players in Argentine history.
siendo uno de los mejores jugadores de la historia argentina.
感谢您成为我世界上最好的父亲和伴侣。
Thank you for being the best father and partner in the world to me.
Gracias por ser el mejor padre y compañero del mundo para mí.
我向你保证，我将永远陪伴你到处鼓励这些颜色。
I promise you that I will always accompany you everywhere to encourage these colors.
Te prometo que te voy a acompañar siempre a todos lados por alentar por estos colores.
我给你写了很多信，但我没有足够的言语来形容我为你感到多么自豪。
I wrote to you a lot more but I don't have enough words to describe how proud I am of you.
Te escribía mucho más pero no me alcanzan las palabras para describir lo orgullosa que tiene vos.
我爱你爸爸。
I love you dad.
Te amo pa.
因为无法度过那个特别的夜晚。
for not being able to be on that special night.
por no poder estar en esa noche tan especial.
为了你，你知道我来这里是为了……
for you and well, you know I'm here trying to...
para vos y bueno, sabes que estoy acá intentando de...
康复以便我可以回来。
to get well so I can come back.
de ponerme bien para ya volver.
我想在场，即使是......
I wanted to be present even if it was...
Quería estar presente aunque sea de...
通过这个视频，以这样的方式，祝愿你
With this video, in this way, I wish you that
con este vídeo, de esta manera, desearte que
你真的很享受那个夜晚，就像你一直以来所做的那样。
that you really enjoyed that night, as you have been doing all this time.
de que disfrute mucho de esa noche, como ha ido haciendo durante todo este tiempo.
在您的选择中，您与您的家人、您所爱的人以及所有...
in the selection, which you enjoyed so special with your family, your loved ones, all the people of...
en la selección, que disfrutaste ya tan especial junto a tu familia, a tus seres queridos, a toda la gente de...
来自阿根廷的人正在表达这种敬意，这种敬意不仅仅是......
from Argentina that is paying this tribute, this tribute more than...
de Argentina que está haciendo este homenaje, este homenaje más que...
你为我们付出的一切，你所做的一切，都是你应得的。
You deserve it for everything you gave us, what you did.
Merecido que tenés por todo lo que nos diste, lo que hiciste.
在个人层面上，我们不再对彼此说出我们必须说的一切，我们很幸运......
On a personal level, we no longer said everything we had to say to each other, we were lucky to...
a nivel personal, ya no dijimos todo lo que teníamos para decirnos, tuvimos la suerte de...
共享一年，共度每一天。
of sharing a year, being together every day.
de compartir un año, estar todos los días juntos.
喝了很多马黛茶，说了很多话，好吧，对吧？
of drinking a lot of mate, a lot of talking and well, right?
de tomar mucho mate, mucha charla y bueno, ¿no?
谁不会这么说...
Who wouldn't say that...
¿Quién no iba a decir que...
在我们经历了所有的选择之后一切都会这样结束
that it would all end this way after everything we went through in the selection of everything
que iba a terminar todo de esta manera después de todo lo que lo que pasamos en la en la selección de todo
一切都活着，除此之外总是
everything lived, beyond that always
todo lo vivido, más allá de que siempre
我们一直很享受在国家队的时光，而且我们总是
We always enjoyed being in the national team and we always
siempre disfrutábamos estar en la selección y siempre
我们希望在同一时刻。
that we wanted to be at the same moment.
que queríamos estar en el mismo momento.
非常努力，谁不会说我们最终会以这种方式赢得我们所拥有的一切
very hard and who wasn't going to say that we were going to end up this way winning everything we
muy duro y quien no iba a decir que íbamos a terminar de esta manera ganando todo lo que
我们在世界冠军、美国冠军和一切冠军中赢得了什么。
what we won in the champions of the world, of America and of everything.
lo que ganamos en los campeones del mundo, de América y de todo.
没什么，享受它，因为你应得的，我爱你。
nothing, enjoy it because you deserve it and I love you.
nada, disfrútalo porque te lo mereces y te amo.
我们会非常想念你，你知道我非常爱你，我总是祝你一切顺利，所以什么都没有。
We are going to miss you a lot, you know that I love you very much and I always wish you the best, so nothing.
Te vamos a extrañar mucho, sabes que te quiero mucho y te deseo siempre lo mejor, así que nada.
我向整个阿根廷致以深深的吻和问候。
I send you a big kiss and greetings to all of Argentina.
Te mando un beso grande y un saludo a toda Argentina.
再见。
See you soon.
Nos vemos pronto.
超。
Chao.
继续！
Go on!
¡Sigue!
关注惊喜！
Follow the surprises!
¡Sigue las sorpresas!
阿根廷足球协会主席克劳迪奥·塔皮亚、南美足球俱乐部主席亚历杭德罗·多明格斯已经在那里，而且……
The president of the Argentine Football Association, Claudio Tapia, of Conmebol, Alejandro Domínguez, is already there, and also...
Ya está el presidente de la Asociación del Fútbol Argentino, Claudio Tapia, de Conmebol, Alejandro Domínguez, y además...
进来的主角，现在收到热烈的掌声是的。
The protagonist who is entering, loud applause to receive now yes.
El protagonista que viene entrando, fuerte el aplauso para recibir ahora sí.
安赫尔·迪·玛丽亚 (Ángel Di María) 和他的家人在这里喝了pintos。
Ángel Di María and his family with the presence of having pintos here.
Ángel Di María y a su familia con la presencia de haber pintos aquí.
那掌声真响亮！
That applause is loud!
¡Fuerte ese aplauso!
让他们坐下，让他们的尖叫声被感受到。
Let them sit, let their screams be felt.
Que se sientan, que se sientan sus gritos.
走吧，走吧！
Let's go, let's go!
¡Vamos, vamos!
这就是想法！
This is the idea!
¡Esta es la idea!
小作品，充满爱，谢谢你所做的一切，我们爱你。
little piece and with a lot of love, thank you for everything, we love you.
pedacito y con mucho amor, gracias por todo, te amamos.
我不会后悔...
I won't regret...
No voy a arrepentirme de...
我的一生
my whole life
mi vida entera
真的。
really.
de verdad.
别忘了我
and don't forget me
y no me olvides
返回。
to return.
en regresar.
如果每一次告别都是海上的一块石头。
If every farewell is a rock on the sea.
Si cada despedida es una roca sobre el mar.
不要忘记我
don't forget me
No me olvides
我住在很远的地方，我请求你怜悯，宝贝。
I live in the distance, I ask you for mercy, baby.
Yo vivo en la distancia, te lo pido por piedad nena.
走吧，走吧！
Let's go, let's go!
¡Vamos, vamos!
走开的时光再次伤害了我
That the time of walking away hurts me once again
Que el tiempo de alejarme Me lastima una vez más
拥抱我一会儿我们爱 Fideo
Hug me for a while We love Fideo
Abrazame un rato Que amamos Fideo
我们从美丽的血小板礼物开始
and we start with the beautiful platelet gifts
y empezamos con los regalos hermosa plaqueta
在总统克劳迪奥·塔皮亚 (Claudio Tapia) 的手中。
In the hands of the president, Claudio Tapia.
En manos del presidente, Claudio Tapia.
亚历杭德罗·多明格斯 (Alejandro Domínguez) 拿着美洲杯的复制品。
and Alejandro Domínguez with a replica of the Copa América.
y Alejandro Domínguez con una réplica de la Copa América.
那条面条将有 36 个标题
it would be 36 titles with that noodle
sería 36 títulos con ese fideos
加油吧伙计们！
Come on guys!
¡Vamos chicos!
就在那里。
There it is.
Ahí está.
还有所有的队友，所有的世界冠军，所有的美国冠军，两届美国冠军。
And all the teammates, all the world champions, all the champions of America, two-time champions of America.
Y todos los compañeros, todos los campeones del mundo, todos los campeones de América, bicampeones de América.
美国，有陪伴
of America, there to accompany
de América, ahí para acompañar
Afideo，我必须把麦克风给你。
Afideo, I have to give you the microphone.
Afideo, te tengo que dar el micrófono.
你知道是这样的。
You know this is so.
Sabés que esto es así.
给大家
to everyone
a todos
事实上，现在能够说话是一个困难的时刻，我内心有很多感受。
The truth is that it is a difficult moment to be able to talk, I have a lot of feelings inside.
La verdad que es un momento difícil de poder hablar, tengo muchos sentimientos por dentro.
首先我要感谢...
First of all I want to thank...
primero que nada quiero agradecer a...
致所有在 AFA 工作的人员。
to all the people who work at the AFA, on the premises.
a toda la gente que trabaja en la AFA, en el predio.
我和他们一起工作了16年，我的整个职业生涯都在他们身边。
I was with them for 16 years, my entire career being by their side.
Fueron 16 años que estuve con ellos, toda mi carrera estando al lado de ellos.
我和他们一起经历了困难的事情。
I experienced difficult things with them.
Viví cosas difíciles con ellos.
最后我也和他们一起度过了很多快乐，他们是一直陪伴在我身边的人。
and in the end I ended up having so many joys with them too, they are the ones who were always by my side.
y al final terminé teniendo tantas alegrías también con ellos, son los que siempre estuvieron al lado.
那些支持我们的人，那些在每次失败后总是面带笑容支持我们的人。
those who supported us, those who were always supporting us with a good face after each defeat.
los que nos bancaron, los que estuvieron siempre apoyándonos con buena cara después de cada derrota.
所以对他们来说这是第一...
So for them it is this first...
Así que para ellos es este primer...
对他们为我所做的一切的爱和感激，当然还有所有路过的孩子。
love and gratitude for everything they did for me and, of course, all the kids who passed by.
cariño y agradecimiento por todo lo que hicieron por mí y por, por obvio, todos los chicos que pasaron.
后来我也不想忘记...
Afterwards I also don't want to forget...
Después también no quiero olvidarme de...
所有的教练，所有经过这里的队友，因为……
of all the coaches, of all the teammates who passed through here because...
de todos los entrenadores, de todos los compañeros que pasaron por acá porque...
我有机会和几代人一起踢球，有机会有伟大的球员在我身边。
I had the chance to play with several generations, to have the chance to have great players by my side.
Tuve la posibilidad de jugar con varias generaciones, de tener la posibilidad de tener grandes jugadores al lado.
那些年我们很不幸没有取得任何成就。
where we were unlucky not to be able to achieve anything in those years.
donde tuvimos la mala suerte de no poder lograr nada en esos años.
以及赢得一切的可能性......
and the possibility of winning everything with...
y la posibilidad de ganar todo con...
今天在场的各位与我分享这一刻。
with the guys who are here today sharing this moment with me.
con los chicos que están hoy acá compartiendo este momento conmigo.
这就是为什么我不想忘记所有同样通过的人并感谢他们，因为他们教会了我继续前进。
That's why I don't want to forget all those who also passed and thank them because they taught me to continue.
Por eso no quiero olvidarme de todos esos que también pasaron y agradecerles porque me enseñaron a seguir.
与之抗争，做很多事情才能继续留在这里。
fighting it, doing many things to be able to continue being here.
peleándola, haciendo muchas cosas para poder seguir estando acá.
因此，也要感谢他们在我职业生涯中教给我的一切。
So thanks to them also for everything they taught me during my career.
Así que gracias a ellos también por todo lo que me fueron enseñando durante mi carrera.
我怎么能忘记这里的所有同事呢？
How can I forget all my colleagues here?
¿Cómo puedo olvidarme de todos mis compañeros acá?
最年轻的，有的已经年纪大了一些，但还很年轻。
Of the youngest ones, some already a little older, who are still young.
De los más chicos, algunos ya un poquito más viejos, que ya son los jóvenes todavía.
这给了我赢得一切的可能性。
that gave me the possibility of winning everything.
que me dieron la posibilidad de poder ganar todo.
我上次在这里获得的一切都感谢他们。
everything I gained this last time here and thanks to them.
todo lo que gané este último tiempo acá y gracias a ellos.
我一直告诉过你这一点，现在我又重复一遍，多亏了这一点，我今天才走上这条路。
I always told you this and I repeat it again, it is thanks to this that today I am going this way.
Siempre se lo dije y lo vuelvo a repetir, es gracias a ello que hoy me estoy yendo de esta manera.
带着这份敬意和所有的爱。
with this tribute and with all this love.
con este homenaje y con todo este cariño.
所以没什么，永远感谢你，我将永远感激不已。
So nothing, thank you eternally, I will be eternally grateful.
Así que nada, agradecerles eternamente, voy a estar eternamente agradecido.
致所有人，致教练组，致医务人员，致所有工作人员，致每一个......
to everyone, to the coaching staff, to the medical staff, to all the staff, to everyone who...
a todos, al cuerpo técnico, al cuerpo médico, a todo el staff, a todos los que...
与我分享了这几年的经历。
shared these last few years with me.
compartido estos últimos años conmigo.
永远感谢你。
Thank you eternally.
Gracias eternamente.
我会感激生活，现在我是另一个粉丝，现在我会和我的家人在一起。
I will be grateful for life and now I am another fan, now I will be up there with my family.
Voy a estar agradecido desde por vida y ahora soy un hincha más, ahora voy a estar ahí arriba con mi familia.
我将继续参加美国世界杯支持他们。
I will continue to be at the World Cups America supporting them.
Voy a seguir estando en las Copas América Mundiales apoyándolos.
我们肯定会继续走这条路，因为它有很多鸡蛋可以继续这样下去。
and surely we will continue on this path because it has a lot of eggs to continue like this.
y seguramente vamos a seguir por este camino porque tiene mucho huevo para seguir así.
最后，因为我现在就想看比赛，所以我也来了。
And now lastly and to finish because I want to see the game now, that's why I came too.
Y ahora por último y terminar porque quiero ver el partido ya, para eso vine también.
我要感谢我的家人，他们在上面。
I want to thank my family who is up there.
Quiero agradecerle a mi familia que está por ahí arriba.
感谢这些年来当事情不顺利时他们给予我的爱。
for the love they gave me all these years when things didn't work out.
por el cariño que me dieron todos estos años cuando las cosas no salían.
我的父母、我的姐妹、全家、我妻子的家人都全力支持我。
My parents, my sisters, the whole family, my wife's family supported me completely.
Me bancaron a full mis viejos, mis hermanas, toda la familia, familia de mi mujer.
也感谢他们一直以来对我的一切支持，这些年来他们所寄托的一切。
Grateful to them also for always supporting me in everything, for banking on everything they banked on during these years.
Agradecido a ellos también por apoyarme siempre en todo, por bancarse todo lo que se bancaron durante estos años.
直到我拥有了这些年来我所拥有的所有快乐。
until I had all this joy that I ended up having in these years.
hasta tener toda esta alegría que terminé teniendo en estos años.
最后，致我生命中最重要的人。
And lastly, to the most important person in my life.
Y último, a la persona más importante de mi vida.
还有我的两位美女，她们一直支持我，陪伴在我身边。
and to my two beauties, who are the ones who always supported me, the ones who were by my side.
y a mis dos preciosuras, que son las que me bancaron siempre, las que estuvieron al lado mío.
那些为我而战的人，那些什么也没留下的人。
The ones who fought for me, the ones who left nothing.
La que lucharon por mí, las que no dejaron nada.
没有什么可以伤害我。
Nothing at all to hurt me.
Nada de nada para que me lastime.
永远感谢你。
Thank you eternally.
Agradecerles eternamente.
感谢您加入我。
Thanks for joining me.
Gracias por acompañarme.
这是我们最终凭借这件球衣赢得的最后一座奖杯。
and this is the last cup that we ended up winning together with this shirt.
y esta es la última copa que terminamos ganando juntos con esta camiseta.
所以没什么，非常感谢你们，我从心底里感谢你们。
So nothing, thank you all very much, I thank you from the bottom of my soul.
Así que nada, muchísimas gracias a todos, les agradezco en el alma.
没什么，我现在将继续站在你们一边支持他们所有人。
And nothing, I will continue to be on your side now supporting all of them.
Y nada, seguiré estando del lado de ustedes ahora apoyando a todos ellos.
所以没什么，非常感谢。
So nothing, thank you very much.
Así que nada, muchas gracias.
谢谢，谢谢。
Thank you, thank you.
Gracias, gracias.
热烈、热烈、热烈的掌声！
Loud, loud, loud the applause!
¡Fuerte, fuerte, fuerte el aplauso!
必须记录下来！
It has to be recorded!
¡Tiene que quedar grabado!
这一声呐喊必须铭刻在安杰尔的心中。
That cry has to be carried in Ángel's heart.
En el corazón de Ángel se tiene que llevar ese grito.
这个领域的，非常强，非常阿根廷。
of this field, very strong, very Argentine.
de esta cancha bien fuerte, bien argentino.
最后的礼物。
The last gift.
El último regalo.
让我们来看看 Fideo 的最后一份礼物。
And let's discover this last gift for Fideo.
Y vamos a descubrir este último regalo para Fideo.
跟它有什么关系呢？
What does it have to do with it?
¿Qué tiene que ver?
拥有足球运动员梦寐以求的最伟大的奖杯。
with the greatest trophy a footballer can dream of.
con el máximo trofeo que puede soñar un futbolista.
世界杯。
The World Cup.
La Copa del Mundo.
以及已经在你手中的美洲杯。
and the Copa América that is already in your hands.
y la Copa América que ya está en sus manos.
被他所有的同伴包围着。
surrounded by all his companions.
rodeado de todos sus compañeros.
我们要去问他，我知道他不喜欢……
We are going to ask him, I know he doesn't like it...
Le vamos a pedir, yo sé que no le gusta...
莱昂内尔、教练组、沃尔特、巴勃罗·拉顿合影。
Leonel for the photo, the coaching staff, Walter, Pablo Ratón.
Leonel para la foto, el cuerpo técnico, Walter, Pablo Ratón.
让我们近距离与全体教练组合影吧。
Let's get closer to the entire coaching staff for the photo.
vamos a acercarnos para la foto a todo el cuerpo técnico
并且全部在一起。
And all together.
Y todos juntos.
就这样，我们准备最后一张照片，有两个小点，就像已经拍摄了很多一样。
There it is, we prepare for the final photo, two little points, like so many have been taken.
Ahí está, nos preparamos para la foto final, dos puntitos, como se han sacado tantas.
最近几次，中间喝了一杯。
in recent times, with a drink in between.
en este último tiempo, con una copa de por medio.
还有巴斯卡拉同伴！
There is the Euskara companion!
¡Ahí está la compañera Euskara!
总统亚历杭德罗·多明格斯 (Alejandro Domínguez) 过来了，菲迪奥的女儿们、他的妻子也去了那里。
Alejandro Domínguez, president, comes over there, Fideo's daughters, his wife goes there too.
Ahí se acerca Alejandro Domínguez, presidente, las hijas de Fideo, vamos la esposa ahí también.
我们微笑着开始闭幕，我想在大家的欢呼声中结束它。
We smiled and began to close, and I want to close it with a shout from all of you.
Sonreímos y empezamos a cerrar, y lo quiero cerrar con el grito de todos ustedes.
让 Fideo 走吧，让他们退出这个 CEPET。
Let Fideo go, let them withdraw from this CEPET.
Que se vaya Fideo, que se retiren de este CEPET.
伴随着所有阿根廷人的战争呐喊，愿他将其深深铭记于心。
with the war cry of all Argentines, may he take it deep into his heart.
con el grito de guerra de todos los argentinos, que se lo lleve bien metido en su corazón.
快点！
Come on!
¡Vamos!
菲德尔！
¡Fidel!